diydoctor.org.uk 2016-11-25

# DIY Doctor Privacy Policy

## Introduction

1.1 We are DIY DOCTOR LIMITED (referred to as "we", “us” and “DIY Doctor”) and we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy when you are visiting any website maintained by us including without limitation the website at www.diydoctor.org.uk and our Facebook, Google+ and Twitter pages and Youtube channel (together the “ **Website** ”) or communicating electronically with us.

1.2 This policy explains what types of personal and non-personal information we collect when you use the Website and the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with this policy, you must cease use of the Website immediately.

1.3 DIY Doctor uses the personal information we collect from you to provide our service to you. We will not rent, sell or share your personal information with any other company for its own marketing purposes without your consent except where mentioned in this policy.

1.4 For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is DIY DOCTOR LIMITED of Suite 2 Block 1 Lakeside Business Park, Mells Frome, Somerset BA11 3RH which is registered with the ICO with registered number [to be confirmed].

## Information We May Collect From You

In order to provide you with the best possible service, we may collect and process the following data about you:

  1. your name
  2. your address
  3. Company details

**Information You Provide Us**

2.2 If you register with us and/or through the Website, we may ask you to provide us with certain personal information.

2.3 There may also be opportunities within the Website to provide additional information. We may use the information you provide us along with your browsing details, to provide you with a better experience when using the Website. We will always provide you with the opportunity to opt out of receiving any communication via email. 

2.4 We may also ask you for information from time to time including when you report a problem with our Website.

**Direct Communications**

2.5 If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

**Surveys**

2.6 We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

**Usage and Browsing Information**

2.7 As part of the standard operation of the Website, we may collect certain non-personal information from you. We may combine this non-personal information with your personal information.

2.8 We may also record details of your visits to and use of the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data and the resources that you access. 

**IP Addresses**

2.9 We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to check aggregate information provided to us by our suppliers. To the extent required we may provide this information to third parties. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

**Information You Provide on Third Party Websites**

2.10 You might find links to third party websites on the Website. These websites should have their own privacy policies which you should check. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies whatsoever as we have no control over them.

## Cookies

3.1 We may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on your browser or the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve the Website and to deliver a better and more personalised service. Some of the cookies we use are essential for the Website to operate.

3.2 If you use the Website, you agree to our use of cookies.

3.3 Please note that third party websites linked to or referenced in the website may also use cookies, over which we have no control. Such cookies (if used) would be downloaded when you click a link on the Website.

3.4 You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of the Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system may issue cookies as soon you visit the Website.

## Google

We use Google Analytics tracking on our website inorder to track and maintain our service and ensure that we are providing the best possible service that we can. As part of the Analytics tracking we also make use of the Display Advertising features included with the application. If you do not like/agree with having certain details tracked then you are free to opt out. [If you would like to opt out please visit the Ad Settings page of your Google account](https://www.google.com/settings/ads "Advert display settings from Google").

In light of the above we can confim that we will not merge any data collected prior to this notice by the DoubleClick cookie unless your have given your concent. If you would like more information on opting out of services provided by Google Analytics [please see further information on the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/ "Find out how to opt out of Google Analytics services in yor browser").

In addition to the above we also make use of the Google Analytics Demographic and Interest reporting features. These features anable us to monitor the age, gender and interest information on our visitors. In turn, this information enables us to fine tune our website to provide the best information, help,advice and products to our users so that our users continue to get the best possible use and service from our website.

## Where We Store Your Personal Data 

4.1 The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

4.2 All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. 

4.3 Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted through our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## Uses Made of the Information

5.1 We use information held about you in the following ways:

  1. to ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  2. to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;
  3. to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
  4. to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so; and
  5. to notify you about changes to our service.

## Mailing List

Our email mailing list is hosted and managed by MailerMailer whose website can be found at [www.mailermailer.com ](http://www.mailermailer.com/ "Mass mailing facilities from MailerMailer").

In our email messages to you which may be distributed through this mailing list, we may provide information from third party providers of products and services which we think may be of interest to you.

If you have subscribed to our email mailing list, but do not wish to receive it in future, please follow the “unsubscribe” instructions contained in each emailed newsletter.

## Forum Area 

This policy explains in detail how “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums” along with its affiliated companies (hereinafter “we”, “us”, “our”, “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums”, “http://www.diydoctor.org.uk/forums”) and phpBB (hereinafter “they”, “them”, “their”, “phpBB software”, “www.phpbb.com”, “phpBB Group”, “phpBB Teams”) use any information collected during any session of usage by you (hereinafter “your information”).

Your information is collected via two ways. Firstly, by browsing “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums” will cause the phpBB software to create a number of cookies, which are small text files that are downloaded on to your computer’s web browser temporary files. The first two cookies just contain a user identifier (hereinafter “user-id”) and an anonymous session identifier (hereinafter “session-id”), automatically assigned to you by the phpBB software. A third cookie will be created once you have browsed topics within “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums” and is used to store which topics have been read, thereby improving your user experience.

We may also create cookies external to the phpBB software whilst browsing “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums”, though these are outside the scope of this document which is intended to only cover the pages created by the phpBB software. The second way in which we collect your information is by what you submit to us. This can be, and is not limited to: posting as an anonymous user (hereinafter “anonymous posts”), registering on “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums” (hereinafter “your account”) and posts submitted by you after registration and whilst logged in (hereinafter “your posts”).

Your account will at a bare minimum contain a uniquely identifiable name (hereinafter “your user name”), a personal password used for logging into your account (hereinafter “your password”) and a personal, valid e-mail address (hereinafter “your e-mail”). Your information for your account at “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums” is protected by data-protection laws applicable in the country that hosts us. Any information beyond your user name, your password, and your e-mail address required by “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums” during the registration process is either mandatory or optional, at the discretion of “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums”. In all cases, you have the option of what information in your account is publicly displayed. Furthermore, within your account, you have the option to opt-in or opt-out of automatically generated e-mails from the phpBB software.

Your password is ciphered (a one-way hash) so that it is secure. However, it is recommended that you do not reuse the same password across a number of different websites. Your password is the means of accessing your account at “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums”, so please guard it carefully and under no circumstance will anyone affiliated with “diydoctor.org.uk DIY and Home Improvement Forums”, phpBB or another 3rd party, legitimately ask you for your password. Should you forget your password for your account, you can use the “I forgot my password” feature provided by the phpBB software. This process will ask you to submit your user name and your e-mail, then the phpBB software will generate a new password to reclaim your account.

## Advertisements

In order to bring you offers and information that may be of interest to you, we may allow third parties to place advertisements on the website. If you choose to click on any advertisement, the advertiser may collect non personally identifiable information such as your domain type, your IP address and clickstream information.

## Disclosure of Your Information

8.1 We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  1. in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  2. if DIY Doctor Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets; and
  3. if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply any agreements we have entered into with you or any third party; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of DIY Doctor Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

## Credit Cards and Payments

Credit card details are not recorded, copied or saved by DIY Doctor. All details are destroyed after 7 days in our possession.

We do not share or sell customer details with any third party.

## Your Rights

9.1 The Act gives you the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [office@diydoctor.org.uk](mailto:office@diydoctor.org.uk "Contact DIY Doctor on office@diydoctor.org.uk").

9.2 The Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

## Access to Information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

## Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [office@diydoctor.org.uk](mailto:office@diydoctor.org.uk "Email DIY Doctor on office@diydoctor.org.uk")
